<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-03-14T09:24:32-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">The Need For Mastering Javascript</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/12/the-need-for-mastering-JavaScript.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Need For Mastering Javascript" /><published>2019-03-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-03-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/03/12/the-need-for-mastering-JavaScript</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/12/the-need-for-mastering-JavaScript.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve realized that I really need to understand basic JavaScript.  However, doing tutorials isn’t enough for me.  I’ve found two potentially useful resources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wes Bos’ &lt;a href=&quot;https://javascript30.com/&quot;&gt;JavaScript30&lt;/a&gt; course&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codewars.com&quot;&gt;CodeWars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;javascript30&quot;&gt;JavaScript30&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Projects help you learn.  What I love about this idea is how it incorporates all of the basics of web development.  Wes Bos has designed projects which will also keep your HTML and CSS skills sharp.  (I guess that’s only true if you decide to make the project look good…)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a list of the projects I’m looking forward to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drum Kit&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ajax Type Ahead (I’ve never used Ajax!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;HTML5 Canvas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Slide in on Scroll&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whack-a-mole!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll be exposing myself to various JavaScript methods and building fun things along the way!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;codewars&quot;&gt;CodeWars&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CodeWars is a website that has the feeling of being a martial arts dojo.  You must pass a test to become a member.  Then, you train by completing various coding challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenges can be tough!  I had one that took me 2 hours to complete, but the learning was worth it.  So far, most of the challenges I’ve had involved manipulating strings and arrays.  Understanding how to work with those data types will be valuable anywhere I go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve had an idea of sharing my thought process of the puzzles while I solve it and then breaking down the &lt;strong&gt;best practice&lt;/strong&gt; answer.  It has amazed me how my answer can be 10+ lines of code and see that the same result could be accomplished as a oneliner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope these resources help you in your journey to understanding JavaScript!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep Evolving!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I’ve realized that I really need to understand basic JavaScript. However, doing tutorials isn’t enough for me. I’ve found two potentially useful resources: Wes Bos’ JavaScript30 course CodeWars</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Codewars Part 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/12/CodeWars-part-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Codewars Part 1" /><published>2019-03-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-03-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/03/12/CodeWars-part-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/12/CodeWars-part-1.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codewars.com&quot;&gt;CodeWars&lt;/a&gt; is a website where you are given challenges and must write code that satisfies requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are some challenges and my thinking behind my answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;challenge-find-the-smallest-integer-in-the-array&quot;&gt;Challenge: Find the smallest integer in the array&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a sorting problem.  My initial reaction is to sort the array from largest to smallest and return the last entry.  I will have to look at some array methods to know what to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I searched on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3schools.com/js/js_array_sort.asp&quot;&gt;W3Schools&lt;/a&gt; for the various array methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several methods of finding the minimum or maximum values of an array.  One is to compare numbers and use the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sort()&lt;/code&gt; method.  For numbers, this requires another function to see if the numbers create a negative, 0, or positive number.  This is because of the hierarchy in numbers.  20 &amp;gt; 100 in computer talk.  :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The method I used was to use the Math method to identify the minimum value.  Here’s the code I copied: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Math.min.apply(null, args)&lt;/code&gt;.  I don’t fully understand the apply or the need for &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;null&lt;/code&gt;.  I will look that up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;apply()&lt;/code&gt; method adds arguments found in an array to an object.  We didn’t have an object, so &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;null&lt;/code&gt; was needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the best practice code: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Math.min(...args)&lt;/code&gt;.
The spread, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;...&lt;/code&gt; gives a comma separated list which the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;min()&lt;/code&gt; can use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;challenge-write-a-program-that-finds-the-summation-of-every-number-from-1-to-number&quot;&gt;Challenge: Write a program that finds the summation of every number from 1 to number&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My idea is to create a variable to keep track of the summation.  Then, run a for-loop until the index variable matches the number given.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hooray!  That happened to be best practice.  However, I saw some answers using an arrow function and the Fibonacci sequence to solve the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s that code: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;const summation = n =&amp;gt; n * (n + 1) / 2;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t see that coming.  I will need to spend time looking at Arrow functions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep Evolving!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">CodeWars is a website where you are given challenges and must write code that satisfies requirements.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Pragmatic Programmer Part 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/11/the-pragmatic-programmer-part-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Pragmatic Programmer Part 1" /><published>2019-03-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-03-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/03/11/the-pragmatic-programmer-part-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/11/the-pragmatic-programmer-part-1.html">&lt;p&gt;There has been one book that has been touted as a must read for programmers: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Pragmatic Programmer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.  I wanted to record my learning as I read it.  It will be documented here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;take-responsibility&quot;&gt;Take responsibility&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is only one person wholly responsible for me: ME!  In the eyes of a programmer, we must take full credit for our work.  This means taking the good &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; the bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you run into problems, then think through possible paths to solve the problem.  People will accept mistakes as long as effort is shown to correct them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-small-leak-leads-to-destruction&quot;&gt;A small leak leads to destruction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This idea hits home a bit hard.  I allow small things to build up.  We think it won’t matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;One paper is okay to leave on the table.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly the entire table is covered…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I’m too tired to put my clothes in the basket.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly the floor is covered with dirty clothes…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One allowance of entropy leads to greater and greater entropy.  Take the time to fix the little things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;eyes-on-the-prize&quot;&gt;Eyes on the prize&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to keep our eyes on the prize.  Don’t lose track of the big picture.  If we get too focused on the minutiae, then our project start to fall apart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;keep-learning&quot;&gt;Keep learning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The authors encourage learning a new programming language each year.  That will keep you on your toes.  I like the idea of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The authors also encourage learning about &lt;strong&gt;normal&lt;/strong&gt; people.  We must understand the user just as much as understanding programmers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;communicate-with-the-audience&quot;&gt;Communicate with the audience&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can’t help others see your vision, then you have no worthy vision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communicating is hard.  Take your time when crafting your message.  Understand your audience so you can communicate in a way they understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good practice to help guide your communication is to develop an outline for your message.  We should never build without a basic outline.  That goes for when we code to when we communicate.  After all, coding is just communicating with a computer…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;dry-off-your-code&quot;&gt;DRY off your code&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DRY stands for &lt;strong&gt;D&lt;/strong&gt;on’t &lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;epeat &lt;strong&gt;Y&lt;/strong&gt;ourself.  The problem with repeating code is when we go back to debug it.  Fixing one error is okay.  Fixing 2 can be manageable.  But once we have to find an error in 3 or more different sections, the frustration level will be sky high!  Therefore, stay &lt;strong&gt;DRY&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;prototype-prototype-prototype&quot;&gt;Prototype, prototype, prototype…&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to start off this section by saying the authors separate ideas that I find to be very similar.  They have three different ideas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tracer Programs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prototyping&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Simple languages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tracer programs are like tracer bullets.  You shoot and see if something works.  Then, you keep building off that design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prototyping is when you build something quick to test it while knowing you won’t actually use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simple languages is a shorthand way of writing out a program without a computer language’s specific syntax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, all of these involve building and testing over and over.  I’m reminded of a psychology study where kindergartners were better at solving a problem than graduate students.  The task was to build a tower out of random materials.  The key component of success for the kindergartners was their constant build-and-test mentality.  If the tower stood, then it was a success.  If it fell, then they rebuilt it.  On the other hand, the graduate students spent so much time planning, they missed out on the ability to test and reevaluate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to keep a mind like the kindergartners.  Don’t become discouraged if your idea falls apart.  Learn from it and build again!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;chapter-3&quot;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;learn-your-tools&quot;&gt;Learn your tools&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don’t know how to properly use your tools, then you will never become a true master.  As programmers, we must learn the basic tools.  For example, get to know your code editor and shell.  If you master those by learning the shortcuts, then your productivity will skyrocket!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best example I have of this is from my Udacity course.  The example was a simple task: move pictures to a new directory.  If I was using the GUI, I could get it done in about a minute.  However, using the shell, I was able to get all the files moved in under 10 seconds.  Typing one line is far faster than creating a new folder, selecting the files, and dragging the files to the new folder using a mouse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep Evolving!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">There has been one book that has been touted as a must read for programmers: The Pragmatic Programmer. I wanted to record my learning as I read it. It will be documented here.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Steps For The Research App</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/10/steps-for-the-research-app.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Steps For The Research App" /><published>2019-03-10T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-03-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/03/10/steps-for-the-research-app</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/10/steps-for-the-research-app.html">&lt;p&gt;There is one very important task that learning to code brings to your attention: PLANNING!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ability to visualize what you are creating is incredibly helpful.  We need something to head toward, something to give meaning to the steps we take.  Without this measure of meaning, we will easily get distracted and lost along the way.  But, this isn’t the only way planning is helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Planning allows us to see what we know and what we need to learn.  If you can walk through a task step-by-step in your mind, then you can conclude you know it.  If you can only &lt;em&gt;see the destination&lt;/em&gt; but don’t know the steps to take, then you can conclude that you need to learn it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below will be my current plan for the research-helping app.  I hope the planning process will give me concrete steps to take toward both the creation of the app and the learning of how to program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-plan&quot;&gt;The Plan&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Design the layout of the app
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;draw the layout (wireframe???)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;include specific html to use (eg) iframe, header, footer)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;does React/Vue have these components???&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Should I use React/Vue/Angular????&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Just CSS Grid for placement?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Code the layout
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Avoid too much CSS at first - get a working prototype&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Key features of the app
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Create Google doc of what the user has typed&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Learn Google doc API
      - Specific guiding questions to help with research&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What’s the goal of this research?
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Full screen modal to help the user focus&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What’s your current idea?
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Full screen modal to help the user focus&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What are some opposing ideas?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What evidence supports your idea?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What evidence supports the opposing ideas?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What can you conclude based on the evidence?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What are your next steps?
      - Highlight and copy text from the iframe browser and automatically include a citation when pasted&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;citation APIs????
      - Continue working on past research&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Having a database of Users????&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is quite a mess.  That means my idea is not fully formed.  I know that drawing out the app and deeply explaining how things will work will be a useful step!  That will be my priority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope seeing the starting, messy stages of creation will help inspire you to continue to take steps!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep Evolving!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">There is one very important task that learning to code brings to your attention: PLANNING!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Gamify Flexbox</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/03/gamify-flexbox.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Gamify Flexbox" /><published>2019-03-03T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-03-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/03/03/gamify-flexbox</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/03/gamify-flexbox.html">&lt;p&gt;I found a fun way to learn using the CSS Flexbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dave Geddes created a game called &lt;a href=&quot;https://mastery.games/p/flexbox-zombies&quot;&gt;Flexbox Zombies&lt;/a&gt;.  It walks you through all of the features of Flexbox while killing off zombie hordes.  It was a fun way to get repetitive practice of using flexbox!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep Evolving!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I found a fun way to learn using the CSS Flexbox.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Purpose Of The App</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/02/23/purpose-of-the-app.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Purpose Of The App" /><published>2019-02-23T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-02-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/02/23/purpose-of-the-app</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/02/23/purpose-of-the-app.html">&lt;p&gt;I heard this piece of advice once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The first step towards anything is to create it first in your brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea may have come from Steven Covey.  I don’t remember.  Maybe one day I will look it up.  Let’s get to the heart of the matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to create an app to help guide people in research.  The app will track the websites for the user.  If the user finds something useful, it will then place a note with a link to the website.  Also, there will be guiding questions to help eliminate cognitive errors in judgment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app will then create a Google Doc with all the notes and links so the research can be easily shared and reviewed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a general idea of the layout.  I want a sidebar on the left with buttons for the guiding questions.  I want a menu at the top where the user can sign in and start or continue research.  I want a place for text so the user can see what will be transferred to the Google Doc.  I also want a browser window for the user to use as research.  Below the browser window will be buttons to move the highlighted words in the mini-browser over to the text field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dream is solidifying.  Now, I need to create what I can to expose the next challenges!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep Evolving!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I heard this piece of advice once.</summary></entry></feed>